another convenient feature of configs is aliases for the commands
for example, if "git config" is long to write I can make an alias for it "git c"
Right now, if I run "git c", then git will not do anything, but instead it will show me the list of commands, that as it think I might mean
But let me make a "git config --global alias.c config".
From now on "c" will mean "config". "git c --list".
Most of the time aliases are used for a longer commands. Usually commands having multiple or long flags.
For instance, let "c" be a "config --global"
And later on — "git c --list" — will give us the global settings. So "c" was substituted with the alias content.
Sometimes theres a need to make an alias for a several commands, so that they are executed one by one.
You can do it by setting the exclamation mark "!"
As a first symbol. Then it can be followed by any commands, not the git commands,
but system commands - shell commands.
And as most of the shells allow to have a list of the commands, followed by a semicolon I've put 2 "echo" commands one after another.
Each of these will print a message. Same approach can be used to run git
Git, do something, semicolon, git, do something else
This screencast will keep the number of aliases to minimum. So that one can open any screencast video and know whats going on.
So that instead of aliases, like "c" or "sayhi" one could see a real git commands. But in the real world aliases
are used quite often, including the usage on the shell level
For example, I've opened one of the settings files of Unix shell and its a lot of aliases here as you can see. "g" for git,
"ga", "gaa" and so on.
One can use a preconfigured set of aliases or, probably you will make your own set of aliases or get the best ones from several sets, so that your resulting set serves you best.